Inventory of the Charles Patrick Carroll papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Research materials
  - Roman law, 1932 (Box 32)
  - Savigny, Friedrich Karl von, 1979 (Box 32)
  - Uses of the Law, 1976-1994 (Box 32)
  - "De lege lata" and "De lege ferenda", 1978 (Box 32)
  - Berger, Raoul, 1978 (Box 33)
  - Bickel, Alex, 1974 (Box 33)
  - Blackmun, Harry, 1975 (Box 33)
  - Bork, Robert, 1991 (Box 33)
  - Bumke, Erwin, 1975-1976 (Box 33)
  - Foucauld, Charles de, 1923 (Box 33)
  - Freud, Sigmund, 1924, 1937 (Box 33)
  - Fromm, Erich (Box 33)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster, 1968 (Box 33)
  - Genetics, 1966-1972 (Box 33)
  - Genocide, 1977-1987 (Box 33)
  - Germany, 1966-1987 (Box 33)
  - Gerstein, Kurt, 1971 (Box 33)
  - Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1976-1981 (Box 33)
  - God, 1980 (Box 33)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1912, 1961 (Box 33)
  - Göring, Hermann, 1989 (Box 33)
  - Kopecky, Lilli, 1982-1994 (Box 33)
    Includes letters from Auschwitz survivor Kopecky to Carroll
  - Kreyche, Robert J., 1973-1975 (Box 33)
    Includes letter to Carroll from Kreyche
  - Kripke, Saul, 1997 (Box 33)
  - The Constitution, 1974 (Box 33)
  - George, VI, King of Great Britain, 1939-1942 (Box 33)
  - Bodelschwingh, Fritz von, 1928-1964 (Box 34)
    Includes letters from Bodelschwingh to Carroll
  - "Briefe aus Italien," Münchener Medizinische Wochenschrift, 1913 (Box 34)
  - Doctors' moral obligation, 1967-1973 (Box 34)
  - Ethics, 1970-1977 (Box 34)
  - Freud, Sigmund, 1948-1986 (Box 34)
  - Gay, Peter, Style in History (Box 34)
  - Genetics, 1970-1972 (Box 34)
  - Infant Doe, 1982 (Box 34)
  - Infanticide, 1940-1987 (Box 34)
  - Jewish perspectives, 1977 (Box 34)
  - Klee, Ernst, 1983 (Box 34)
  - Der Mensch und sein Tod, 1977 (Box 34)
  - Suicide, 1965-1983 (Box 34)
    Includes essay by Carroll
  - Suizid und Euthanasie als human- und sozialwissenschaftliches Problem, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Swift, Jonathan, 1983 (Box 34)
  - Wannsee Conference, 1987 (Box 34)
    Includes letter and speech by Lilli Kopecky
  - Zentrale Stelle der Landesjustizverwaltungen, Ludwigsburg, 1922-1945 (Box 34)
  - Film script on euthanasia by Herman Schweninger, 1940-1943 (Box 34)
  - Bibliography, 1975-1990 (Box 34)
  - Brain death, 1974-1993 (Box 34)
  - Church and religious leaders, 1937-1993 (Box 34)
  - Doctors, 1939-1976 (Box 34)
  - Euthanasie und Vernichtung "lebensunwerten" Lebens unter Berücksichtigung des behinderten Menschen, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Hadamar Euthanasia Center, 1945 (Box 35)
    Includes partial list of victims
  - Hartheim Euthanasia Center, 1944-1976 (Box 35)
  - Die Innere Mission. Monatsblatt des Central-Ausschusses für die Innere Mission der deutschen evangelischen Kirche, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Medical ideology, 1966 (Box 35)
  - Right to die, 1970-1977 (Box 35)
  - Ethics
    - Medical ethics, 1968-1988 (Box 36)
    - Scientific ethics, 1975 (Box 36)
    - Press, 1956-1998 (Box 36)
    - Bioethics, 1968-1977 (Box 36)
  - Eugenics, 1964-1980 (Box 36)
  - Entropy (Box 36)
  - Encephalitis, 1975 (Box 36)
  - Erasmus, 1978 (Box 36)
  - Holocaust - conferences, 1941-1991 (Box 36)
  - Haushofer, Karl (Box 36)
  - Heart transplants, 1964-1975 (Box 37)
  - Heidegger, Martin, 1976-1983 (Box 37)
  - Helping others (Box 37)
  - Hillesum, Etty, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Hitler, Adolf
    - Adolf Hitler, by John Toland, 1976 (Box 37)
    - Hitler's physicists, 1978-1981 (Box 37)
    - Hitlers Tischgespräche im Führerhauptquartier, 1941-42, 1951 (Box 37)
    - Hoffmann, Heinrich, 1955 (Box 37)
    - The Psychopathic God: Adolf Hitler, by Robert G.L. Waite, 1975-1999 (Box 37)
  - Holocaust
    - Allied errors, 1977 (Box 37)
    - Art, 1987 (Box 37)
  - Human Sexual Activity, Committee on, 1977-1979 (Box 37)
    Includes directives from the Episcopal Institute of Theological Studies and materials regarding the church's view of homosexuality
  - National Organization of Episcopalians For Life, 1985-1986 (Box 37)
  - Quinlan, Karen, 1975-1976 (Box 37)
  - AIDS, 1986-1987 (Box 38)
  - Apartheid, 1983 (Box 38)
  - Bishop of Durham (David Jenkins), 1984 (Box 38)
  - Brown, Anthony Cave, 1975 (Box 38)
  - Buckley, William F., 1978, 1982 (Box 38)
  - Child health, 1976 (Box 38)
  - Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints, 1985 (Box 38)
  - Cogley, John, 1976 (Box 38)
  - Context: a commentary on the interaction of religion and culture, 1972-1974 (Box 38)
  - Deutsche Briefe 1934-1938: ein Blatt der katholischen Emigration, 1969 (Box 38)
  - Ernst, Siegfried, 1939-1986 (Box 38)
    Includes copies of Medizin und Ideologie: Informationsblatt der Europäischen Årzteaktion, 1982-1986
  - Evangelische Kirche (Deutsche Demokratische Republik), 1984-1985 (Box 38)
  - Extraterrestrial cultures, 1985 (Box 38)
  - German views of America, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Gospel of Peter, 1963-1980 (Box 38)
  - Graham, Billy, 1975-1983 (Box 38)
  - Greer, Germaine, 1984 (Box 38)
  - Greene, Graham, 1982 (Box 38)
  - Aschaffenburg, Gustav, Die Sicherung der Gesellschaft gegen gemeingefährliche Geisteskranke, 1912 (Box 39)
  - Atrocities and Other Conditions in Concentration Camps in Germany, 1945 (Box 39)
  - Auschwitz and I.G. Farben, 1957 (Box 39)
  - Bayle, François, Croix gammée contre caducée; les expériences humaines en Allemagne pendant la deuxième Guerre mondiale, 1950 (Box 39)
  - Bevölkerungsfragen, 1935-1936 (Box 39)
  - Bombing of Auschwitz, 1944-1987 (Box 39)
  - Abortion laws, 1971-1975 (Box 40)
  - Adler, H.G., Der verwaltete Mensch: Studien zur Deportation der Juden aus Deutschland, 1974 (Box 40)
  - Armitage, Henry G., Jr., 1973-1978 (Box 40)
    Mainly correspondence related to the pro-life movement
  - Amnesty International report on torture, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Fun with the Environment, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Germany
    - External debts, 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Have We the Courage to Remember? Reflections upon the Politicization of Law and Medicine before and in the Third Reich," by Charles Carroll (Box 40)
  - Gemeinder, Artur, Die Euthanasie (Sterbehilfe), 1938 (Box 40)
  - Gesetz zur Verhütung erbkranken Nachwuchses vom 14. Juli 1933: nebst Ausführungsverordnungen, 1936-1974 (Box 40)
    Includes reports on the implementation of the law
  - Genetics, 1975 (Box 40)
  - Gilbert, G.M., Nuremberg Diary, 1947 (Box 40)
  - Grant, Madison, 1916-1946 (Box 40)
  - Gu¨nther, Hans F.K., Ritter, Tod und Teufel: der heldische Gedanke, 1937 (Box 40)
  - Engisch, Karl, 1948, 1973 (Box 41)
  - Euthanasia (Council of Europe), 1975-1976 (Box 41)
  - Ferrar, Nicholas, 1980 (Box 41)
  - Fischer, Alfons, Geschichte des deutschen Gesundheitswesens, 1965 (Box 41)
  - Fittkau, Gerhard A., 1958 (Box 41)
  - Fleming, Peter, Operation Sea Lion, 1957 (Box 41)
  - Freisler, Roland, Das rechtsdenken des jungen Europa (Box 41)
  - Friedländer, Erich, "Meine Erlebnisse in der Hitlerzeit" (Box 41)
  - Friedrich, Carl J., Die Philosophie des Rechts in historischer Perspektive., 1955 (Box 41)
  - Borcherding, Friedrich, Die Abtreibung der Leibesfrucht nach dem Reichsstrafgesetzbuch in alter und neuer Fassung, 1926 (Box 42)
  - Drogin, Elasah, 1979 (Box 42)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1946 (Box 43)
  - Doktorgrades (doctorate), 1897 (Box 43)
    Includes Satzungen und Bedingungen für die Erwerbung des Doktorgrades bei den medizinischen Fakultäten der deutschen Universitäten
  - Dying We Live: The Final Messages and Records of the Resistance, 1956 (Box 43)
  - Ebermayer, Ludwig, Der Arzt und der Staat, 1928 (Box 43)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1971 (Box 43)
  - Euthanasia
    - Meltzer, Ewald, Das Problem der Abkrüzung des 'lebensunwerten' Lebens, 1925 (Box 43)
    - Right to die, 1974 (Box 43)
    - Euthanasie: das Problem der Vernichtung lebensunwerten Lebens, 1924 (Box 43)
    - Clippings
      - Årztliches Intelligenz-Blatt. Organ für Bayerns staatliche und o¨ffentliche Heilkunde, 1856 (Box 43)
      - Annalen des Charité-Krankenhaus zu Berlin, 1860 (Box 43)
      - Gazette hebdomadaire de médecine et de chirurgie, 1859-1864 (Box 43)
      - Archiv für pathologische Anatomie und Physiologie und für klinische Medizin, 1885 (Box 43)
      - Archiv für Gynäkologie, 1885, 1892 (Box 43)
      - Berliner klinische Wochenschrift, 1888, 1892 (Box 43)
      - Archiv für Dermatologie und Syphilis, 1894 (Box 43)
      - Zentralblatt für Gynäkologie, 1893 (Box 43)
      - Deutsche medizinische Wochenschrift, 1925 (Box 43)
      - Medizinische Klinik, 1935 (Box 43)
      - Münchener medizinische Wochenschrift, 1937 (Box 43)
      - Münchener medizinische Wochenschrift, 1931 (Box 43)
      - Bulletin de l'Académie nationale de me´decine, 1851-1852 (Box 43)
  - Fabrice, Heinrich von, Die Lehre von der Kindsabtreibung und vom Kindesmord. Gerichtsärztliche Studien, 1911 (Box 43)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1968 (Box 44)
    Includes report on Soviet-American Peace Committee
  - Bethe, Hans A., 1979 (Box 44)
  - Campbell, Donald T., 1975 (Box 44)
  - Charny, Israel W., How Can We Commit the Unthinkable? Genocide: The Human Cancer, 1982 (Box 44)
  - Chemical warfare, 1969 (Box 44)
  - Cities, 1975 (Box 44)
  - Clausewitz, Carl von, 1991 (Box 44)
  - Conference, "Euthanasia: The Life and Death Debate of the 90s," Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1990-1991 (Box 44)
  - Cost-benefit analysis in medicine, 1979-1984 (Box 44)
  - Genest, Jacques, 1977 (Box 44)
  - Grass, Günter, 1970 (Box 44)
  - Heroes and perpetrators of the Holocaust, 1990-1998 (Box 44)
  - Heyde, Werner, 1961 (Box 44)
  - Hoffmann, Lillian, on Soviet Jewry, 1989 (Box 44)
  - Holocaust, 1934-1980 (Box 44)
  - Ivy, Andrew C., 1970 (Box 44)
  - Kant, Immanuel, 1892-1913 (Box 44)
  - Law, 1923-1995 (Box 44)
  - Bucheit, Gert, Richter in roter Robe; Freisler, Präsident des Volksgerichtshofes, 1968 (Box 45)
  - Bukovskii, Vladimir Konstantinovich, 1972 (Box 45)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N., 1931 (Box 45)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1959 (Box 45)
  - Christian Solidarity International, 1985 (Box 45)
  - Church history, 1972 (Box 45)
  - Clauberg, Carl, 1957 (Box 45)
  - Clausewitz, Carl von, 1971 (Box 45)
  - Constitutions of German Länder, 1977 (Box 45)
  - Craig, Gordon, 1971 (Box 45)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1968-1975 (Box 45)
  - Denazification, 1949, 1980 (Box 45)
  - Diocese of California, 1973 (Box 45)
  - Adenauer, Konrad, 1976 (Box 46)
  - Adler, Mortimer, 1982 (Box 46)
  - Adolph, Walter, Im Schatten des Galgens: zum Gedächtnis der Blutzeugen in der national-sozialistischen Kirchenverfolgung, 1953-1965 (Box 46)
  - Alcohol (abortion and euthanasia) (Box 46)
  - Buber, Martin, 1981 (Box 46)
  - Goldhagen, Daniel Jonah, 1996 (Box 46)
  - Hegel, Georg Wilhelm Friedrich, 1907-1961 (Box 46)
  - Karski, Jan, 1996-1997 (Box 46)
  - Kimminich, Otto, Naturrecht -- positives Recht -- Menschenrechte, 1982 (Box 46)
  - Kirchliche Akten über die Reichskonkordatsverhandlungen 1933, 1969 (Box 46)
  - Lichtenberg, Bernhard, 1963 (Box 46)
  - Lifton, Robert Jay, 1982 (Box 46)
  - Lukacs, John, 1945: Year Zero, 1978 (Box 46)
  - Mayer, Joseph, 1927-1982 (Box 46)
  - Black heroes, 1982 (Box 47)
  - Culture wars, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Ernst, Siegfried, 1939-1992 (Box 47)
    Relates to the pro-life movement. Includes photograph of Charles Carroll
  - Euthanasia: then and now, 1934-1998 (Box 47)
  - History of medicine, 1913- 1919 (Box 47)
  - Human rights, 1970-1994 (Box 47)
  - Human values, 1967-1977 (Box 47)
  - Third Reich and medicine, 1973-1998 (Box 47)
    Includes notes by Carroll on his book project
  - Drug abuse, 1969-1975 (Box 48)
  - Dutch doctors, 1982 (Box 48)
  - Hitler Youth, 1976 (Box 48)
  - Holocaust
    - Abortion, 1977-1997 (Box 48)
    - Ahnenerbe, 1947 (Box 48)
    - Children of Nazis, 1988 (Box 48)
    - Chronology, 1984 (Box 48)
    - Churches, 1972-1998 (Box 48)
    - Treblinka, 1967 (Box 48)
    - Vernichtungslagern (extermination camps), 1976 (Box 48)
  - Huntington Disease, 1983 (Box 48)
  - Ideology, 1976 (Box 48)
  - Illegitimate children, 1944, 1973 (Box 48)
  - Illich, Ivan (Box 48)
  - In vitro fertilization (IVF), 1973-1992 (Box 48)
  - Individualism, 1972 (Box 48)
  - Infanticide, 1992 (Box 48)
  - Informed consent, 1980 (Box 48)
  - Ingelfinger, Franz, 1972-1973 (Box 48)
  - Institut de la vie (Box 48)
  - Institutionalization, 1980 (Box 48)
  - Iona Community, 1985 (Box 48)
  - Dyck, Arthur J. (Box 48)
  - Experimentation on humans, 1951-1988 (Box 49)
  - Gierke, Otto von, Johannes Althusius und die Entwicklung der naturrechtlichen Staatstheorien: zugleich ein Beitrag zur Geschichte der Rechtssystematik, 1958 (Box 49)
  - Goya, Francisco, 1976 (Box 49)
  - Growth hormone therapy, 1989 (Box 49)
  - Guderian, Heinz, 1961 (Box 49)
  - Hawking, Stephen, 1990 (Box 49)
  - Holocaust
    - Albertson, Gertrude, Walpurgis Night: Stories about Growing up in Nazi Germany, an Eye Witness Account, 1984 (Box 49)
    - Auschwitz, 1978-1984 (Box 49)
    - Bibliography and notes, 1967-1987 (Box 49)
    - Mitzner, Ken, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
      Includes letter and writings by Mitzner regarding the pro-life movement
  - Medizin und Ideologie: Informationsblatt der Europäischen Årzteaktion, 1983-1994 (Box 49)
  - "Survey on Antisemitic Events", 1983 September-October (Box 49)
  - Barmen Declaration, 1934-1986 (Box 49)
  - The Enlightenment, 1990 (Box 50)
  - Fassbender, Wilhelm (Box 50)
  - Florovsky, Georges, 1972-1976 (Box 50)
  - Frederick II, King of Prussia, 1973 (Box 50)
  - French Revolution, 1983-1989 (Box 50)
  - Shirer, William L., 1943 (Box 50)
  - Soviet medicine, 1975 (Box 50)
  - Speer, Albert, 1971-1980 (Box 50)
  - Spina bifida, 1978-1981 (Box 50)
  - State as chief physician, 1976 (Box 50)
  - Statistics, 1968-1976 (Box 50)
    Mainly about abortion
  - Sterilization, 1970-1994 (Box 50)
  - Vaccination, 1932 (Box 50)
  - Vanier, Jean, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Handicapped people, 1973-1988 (Box 51)
  - Health care, 1975-1988 (Box 51)
  - Health education, 1969-1976 (Box 51)
  - Henderson, Arthur, 1938 (Box 51)
  - Herbert, George (Box 51)
  - Hereditary and racial policy in Germany, 1935 (Box 51)
  - Hilberg, Raul, 1985 (Box 51)
  - Hippocrates, 1970-1991 (Box 51)
  - History (Box 51)
  - Holocaust, 1979-1992 (Box 51)
  - Haberer, Joseph, Politics and the Community of Science, 1969 (Box 52)
  - Hahn, Otto, 1970 (Box 52)
  - Harris, Whitney, Tyranny on Trial, 1954 (Box 52)
  - Heindl, Robert, Der Berufsverbrecher, 1926 (Box 52)
  - Helsinki Declaration, 1964 (Box 52)
  - Heschel, Abraham Joshua, 1973 (Box 52)
  - Hess, Rudolf, 1974 (Box 52)
  - Hitler, Adolf
    - Das Deutschland Adolf Hitlers: die ersten vier Jahre des Dritten Reiches, 1937, 1983 (Box 52)
    - "The Woman Who Explored the Consciences of the Men From Hitler's Extermination Camps: Gitta Serney", 1974 (Box 52)
    - Hitler, by Joachim C. Fest, 1974-1975 (Box 52)
  - Hoche, Alfred, "Über die Gefährlichkeit Geisteskranker", 1904 (Box 52)
  - Hoche, Alfred, Die Freiheit des Willens, 1902 (Box 52)
  - Höfele, Karl Heinrich. Geist und Gesellschaft der Bismarckzeit, 1967 (Box 52)
  - Holborn, Hajo, Republic to Reich, 1972 (Box 52)
  - Holland. Account by Dutch Jew on his wartime experience, 1945 (Box 52)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendall, 1943 (Box 52)
  - Human dignity, 1966-1991 (Box 53)
  - Human experimentation, 1966-1997 (Box 53)
  - The Humanist clippings, 1968-1981 (Box 53)
  - Humanhood, 1975-1991 (Box 53)
  - Hospitals, 1935-1985 (Box 53)
  - Hudal, Alois, 1976 (Box 53)
  - Jehovah's Witnesses, 1985 (Box 53)
  - Job (Biblical figure), 1983 (Box 53)
  - Judaism, 1962 (Box 53)
  - Judges, 1986 (Box 53)
  - July 20, 1944 (Hitler assassination attempt), 1984 (Box 53)
  - 1974 (Box 53)
  - Kaiser-Wilhelm-Gedächtniskirche (Box 53)
  - Kálnoky, Ingeborg, 1974 (Box 53)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1911 (Box 53)
  - Kaplan, Mordecai, 1983 (Box 53)
  - Kass, Leon, 1980-1985 (Box 53)
  - Kedourie, Elie, 1981 (Box 53)
  - Kelly, George Armstrong, 1984 (Box 53)
  - Keniston, Kenneth (Box 53)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde, 1944 (Box 53)
  - Koestler, Arthur, 1941-1976 (Box 53)
  - Kolbe, Maximilian, 1971-1982 (Box 53)
  - Konopka, Gisela, 1972-1978 (Box 53)
  - Koop, C. Everett, 1980-1981 (Box 53)
  - Kopecky, Lilli, Im Schatten der Flammen: sechs Vorlesungen über den Holocaust, 1992 (Box 53)
    Includes letter from Kopecky to Carroll
  - Kühl, Stefan, 1994 (Box 53)
  - Jews
    - Jewish-Christian dialogue, 1984-1988 (Box 54)
      Includes essays by Carroll
    - "Jews and Germans at the Turn of the Century", 1976 (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1998 (Box 54)
    - Prager, Dennis, Why the Jews?: The Reason for Antisemitism, 1983 (Box 54)
    - Sellner, Albert, Der Ursprung von Monotheismus und Judenhass, 1988 (Box 54)
    - Soviet Jewry, 1985 (Box 54)
  - Johnson, Gustaf F., Hearts Aflame, 1970 (Box 54)
  - Jonas, Hans, 1968-1977 (Box 54)
  - Kittel, Gerhard, Theologians Under Hitler, 1985 (Box 54)
  - Israel, 1982-1990 (Box 54)
  - Jägerstätter, Franz, 1973 (Box 55)
  - Justice, 1984-1985 (Box 55)
  - Justice and National Socialism, 1970 (Box 55)
  - Lebensborn, 1980 (Box 55)
  - Lejeune, Jérôme, 1968-1986 (Box 55)
  - Lethal injections, 1978-1985 (Box 55)
  - Liberation (men's and women's), 1973-1986 (Box 55)
  - Die Militärärztlichen Akademie, 1939 (Box 55)
  - Napoleonic Wars, 1973 (Box 55)
  - Nuremberg
    - Nuremberg Code, 1945-1993 (Box 55)
    - Licht in den Schatten der Vergangenheit: zur Enttabuisierung der Nürnberger Kriegsverbrecherprozesse, 1987 (Box 55)
    - A Study in Public International Law: Comparing the Trial of Adolf Eichmann in Jerusalem with the Trial of the Major German War Criminals at Nuremberg, 1973 (Box 55)
  - Science and law, 1970-1975 (Box 55)
  - Strafgesetzbuch, Strafprozessordnung, Gerichtsverfassungsgesetz: nebst den wichtigsten Nebengesetzen; zusammengestellt nach dem Stand vom 1. Oktober 1935 (Box 55)
  - Justiz und NS-Verbrechen: Sammlung deutscher Strafurteile wegen nationalsozialistischer Tötungsverbrechen 1945-1966, Band I-XIX, 1968 (Box 56)
  - Last Temptation of Christ (movie), 1988-1991 (Box 57)
  - Liberation, 1985 (Box 57)
  - Life in Old Testament and New Testament, 1975 (Box 57)
  - Life, theology of (Box 57)
  - Lilje, Hanns, 1977 (Box 57)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1985 (Box 57)
  - Linkage (Nazis and abortion), 1978-1985 (Box 57)
  - Living wills, 1984-1989 (Box 57)
  - Lorenz, Konrad, 1973- 1975 (Box 57)
  - Louisell, David, 1973 (Box 57)
  - Lustiger, Jean-Marie, 1946 (Box 57)
  - Luther, Martin, 1809-1986 (Box 57)
  - Lynch, William, 1975 (Box 57)
  - Lysenko, Trofim (Box 57)
  - Malpractice, 1975 (Box 57)
  - Marcel, Gabriel, 1972 (Box 57)
  - Marriage, 1973-1981 (Box 57)
  - Martyrs, 1986 (Box 57)
  - Marx and Marxism, 1979-1981 (Box 57)
  - Media re: abortion, 1972-1981 (Box 57)
    Includes letters to the editor by Carroll
  - Medical costs, 1977-1984 (Box 57)
  - Medical education, 1967 (Box 57)
  - Medical ethics, 1969-1991 (Box 57)
  - Medical history, 1971-1982 (Box 57)
  - Medicare, November 1984 (Box 57)
  - Medicine
    - Eppinger, Hans, 1985-1986 (Box 57)
    - Medical law, 1964-1970 (Box 57)
    - Medical terms: German-English, 1929-1979 (Box 57)
    - Medicine and Halakhah (Jewish law), 1989 (Box 57)
    - Medizin im Nationalsozialismus, 1980 (Box 58)
    - 1967 (Box 58)
    - Philosophy of medicine, 1952-1988 (Box 58)
    - Physicians, 1962-1986 (Box 58)
    - Research, 1980 (Box 58)
    - Tuskegee Syphilis Study, 1982 (Box 58)
  - The Memoirs of Captain Liddell Hart, 1965 (Box 58)
  - Mengele, Josef, 1978-1986 (Box 58)
  - Menninger, Karl (Box 58)
  - Menstrual extraction, 1973 (Box 58)
  - Mental illness, 1974-1975 (Box 58)
  - Mental retardation, 1970-1985 (Box 58)
  - Meteorology, 1964 (Box 58)
  - Metzger, Max Josef, 1942-1985 (Box 58)
  - Milch, Erhard (Box 58)
  - Military channeling, 1968 (Box 58)
  - Mondale Committee, 1968 (Box 58)
  - Monod, Jacques, 1972 (Box 58)
  - Morality, 1975-1993 (Box 58)
  - Motherhood, 1958-1975 (Box 58)
  - Mudge, Lewis, "Jesus and the Sociological Imagination", 1970 (Box 58)
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1973 (Box 58)
  - Murder, 1975 (Box 58)
  - Myers, Kilmer (Episcopal Bishop of California), 1967-1971 (Box 58)
    Scope and Contents notes
  - Population Explosion, 1967-1994 (Boxes 59)
  - Premature infants, 1939-1981 (Box 59)
  - The press, 1973-1993 (Box 59)
  - Price, Walter K. Next Year In Jerusalem, 1975 (Box 59)
  - Primum non nocere, newsletter of the World Federation of Doctors who Respect Human Life, 1980 (Box 59)
  - Prisoners of war, 1939-1980 (Box 59)
  - Privacy, 1966 (Box 59)
  - Progesterone, 1986-1987 (Box 59)
  - Promiscuity and infertility, 1977 (Box 59)
  - Prostaglandins, 1972-1975 (Box 59)
  - Psychology, 1974 (Box 59)
  - Psychosurgery, 1973 (Box 59)
  - Psychotherapy and the Nazis, 1984 (Box 59)
  - Public health in Germany, 1986 (Box 59)
  - Public opinion, 1981 (Box 59)
  - Quality of Life, 1968-1983 (Box 59)
  - Quay, Paul, Morality by Calculation of Values, 1975 (Box 59)
  - Race, 1967-1989 (Box 59)
  - Race and immigration, 1978 (Box 59)
  - Racial hygiene, 1986-1989 (Box 59)
  - Rape, 1972-1973 (Box 59)
  - Red Cross, 1988 (Box 60)
  - Rhetoric, 1965-1994 (Box 60)
  - Rickover, Hyman George, 1974 (Box 60)
  - Right to die, 1982-1987 (Box 60)
  - Right to health care, 1989 (Box 60)
  - Rilke, Rainer Maria, 1975 (Box 60)
  - Ringelblum, Emanuel, 1983 (Box 60)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1974-1975 (Box 60)
  - Rommel, Erwin, 1953 (Box 60)
  - Rome, Club of, 1972-1975 (Box 60)
  - Rosenbergs Mythus und evangelischer Glaube: ein Gemeindevortrag, by Wilhelm Florin, 1935 (Box 60)
  - Mendelsohn, John, Trial by Document: The Use of Seized Records in the United States Proceedings at Nuernberg, 1975-1988 (Box 60)
  - Medical ethics
    - Teaching right from wrong, 1968-1987 (Box 60)
    - Garrett Hardin on rights, 1968-1980 (Box 60)
    - Do not resuscitate, 1982-1986 (Box 60)
    - Wrongful life, 1970-1994 (Box 60)
  - Rosenberg, Alfred, 1935-1985 (Boxes 61)
  - Rosenblum, Victor, 1981 (Box 61)
  - Ruta, Dear God, I Wanted to Live, 1979 (Box 61)
  - Rutherford Institute, 1983-1991 (Box 61)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1975-1980 (Box 61)
  - Sakharov, Andrei, 1973-1975 (Box 61)
  - Sauerbruch, Ferdinand, 1920 (Box 61)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, 1956-1990 (Box 61)
  - Schwann, Theodor (Box 61)
  - Shcharansky, Anatoly, 1986 (Box 61)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1973 (Box 61)
  - Schröder, Rudolf Alexander, 1987 (Box 61)
  - Schopenhauer, Arthur, 1975 (Box 61)
  - Science and religion, 1945-1972 (Box 61)
  - Science, man, and society, 1964-1987 (Box 61)
  - Raffalt, Reinhard, Wohin steuert der Vatikan?, 1973 (Box 62)
  - Rahner, Karl, 1970-1984 (Box 62)
  - Ramsey, Paul, 1949-1987 (Box 62)
  - Rand, Ayn, 1976-1979 (Box 62)
  - Rascher, Sigmund, 1941 (Box 62)
  - Ratner, Herbert, 1958-1989 (Box 62)
    Includes a letter from Ratner to Carroll
  - Reck-Malleczewen, Fritz Percy, Diary of a Man in Despair, 1970 (Box 62)
  - Salanter, Israel, 1983 (Box 62)
  - Schrödinger, Erwin, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Schulweiss, Harold, 1984 (Box 62)
  - Schweizer, Eduard, 1987 (Box 62)
  - Senior, John, 1978 (Box 62)
  - Secrecy, 1978 (Box 63)
  - Secular humanism, 1985 (Box 63)
  - Semmelweis, Ignác (Box 63)
  - Sex clinics, 1976-1988 (Box 63)
  - Sex education, 1975-1976 (Box 63)
  - Sex selection, 1975-1988 (Box 63)
  - Sexual deviation, 1976 (Box 63)
  - Sexual discrimination (Box 63)
  - Sexual involvement in counseling and pastoral work, 1986-1988 (Box 63)
  - Sexuality, 1966-1995 (Box 63)
  - Shakespeare, William (Box 63)
  - Shockley, William, 1968-1973 (Box 63)
  - Siegel, Seymour, 1984 (Box 63)
  - Sigerist, Henry Ernst, The Great Doctors: A Biographical History of Medicine, 1933 (Box 63)
  - Simpson, Nora Ann (sterilization) (Box 63)
  - Single parents, 1975-1976 (Box 63)
  - Singer, Peter, 1974-1991 (Box 63)
  - Savigny, Friedrich Karl von, Vom Beruf unserer Zeit für Gesetzgebung und Rechtswissenschaft, 1892 (Box 64)
  - Schönfeld, Walther, Die Geschichte der Rechtswissenschaft im Spiegel der Metaphysik, 1943 (Box 64)